

Computer Vision Researcher

NATIONALITY: Dutch | PRONOUNS: she/her/hers.

Roles: Researcher, adviser, lecturer, invited speaker, computer scientist.

Email: Silvia[dot]Laura[dot]Pintea[at]gmail[dot]com Webpage: http://silvialaurapintea.github.io

My work is in the field of AI, specifically Computer Vision and Deep Learning, where I have extensive experience with video and image analysis, specifically scale-invariance, video motion representations and regression problems.

My current focus is on effective video analysis and robust motion representations.

Work Experience

Job Description

Job Description

Period

Period

Period

Period

Division of Image Processing (LKEB), LUMC, Leiden, NL Senior PostDoc (Guest researcher) Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology (TUDelft), Delft, NL Job Description Efficient video and motion representations towards surgery video analysis.

May 2022 — Present

Researcher Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology (TUDelft), Delft, NL

Focus on Deep Learning scale-invariance and efficiency.

July 2020 — February 2022

Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology (TUDelft), Delft, NL PostDoc

> Collaboration with LUMC and the Geophysics department at TUDelft. Working on image and video analysis: geometric priors, scale-invariance, video representations, etc.

July 2016 — July 2020

R&D Engineer Layar/Blippar, Amsterdam, NL

Job Description Efficient large-scale image matching and retrieval.

January — June 2016

EDUCATION

PhD Computer Vision, University of Amsterdam (UvA), Amsterdam, NL Focus Motion prediction, object localization, video representation learning Thesis Title Continuous Learning in Computer Vision Period 2011 - 2015MScArtificial Intelligence, University of Amsterdam, (UvA) Amsterdam, NL Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Neural Networks, Game Theory. Focus Period | Avg. Grade 2009 – 2011 | 8.31 (out of 10) Computer Science, University of Bucharest, Faculty of Mathematics and Computer BScScience, Bucharest, RO Algorithms and data structures, Object oriented programming, Formal methods. Focus Period | Avg. grade 2005 - 2008 | 9.40 (out of 10)

KEY PUBLICATIONS

- "A step towards understanding why classification helps regression" SL Pintea, Y. Lin, J. Dijkstra, JC van Gemert, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2023.
- "Resolution learning in deep convolutional networks using scale-space theory", SL Pintea, N Tomen, SF Goes, M Loog, JC van Gemert, Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), 2021.
- "No frame left behind: Full Video Action Recognition", X Liu, SL Pintea, FK Nejadasl, O Booij, JC van Gemert. Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.
- "Déjà Vu: Motion Prediction in Static Images.", SL Pintea, JC van Gemert, AWM Smeulders, European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2014.

Complete list of publications: https://scholar.google.nl/citations?user=shTkx9EAAAAJ&hl=en

QUALIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

University teaching qualifications (TUDelft), completed in 2022. BKO

PDPTenure Track Personal Development Program (TUDelft), completed in 2021.

TEACHING AND GUIDING

Course responsible BSc Image Processing course (2021-2022), BSc Image Processing course (2017-2022), Lecturer

MSc Computer Vision course at TUDelft (2018-2022)

MSC ADVISER Tobias Stahl, Yichao Zhang, Chengqiu Zhang, Xilin Li, Yue Liu, Omar Hommos, Xi-

aoming Wen, Jian Zheng, Ziyu Bao, Yordan Dimitrov, Nikhil Saldanha, Ziyu Bao,

Jimmy Vlekke, Frans de Boer, Douwe Hoonhout

Xin Liu, Yancong Lin, Vedran Vukotic (visting student), Abolfazi Nadi (visiting stu-PhD adviser

PhD copromotor Dr. Yancong Lin, Dr. Xin Liu

TEACHING ASSISTANT BSc Short Course on Pattern Recognition (2017-2019)

COMMUNITY SERVICE & ADDITIONAL INFO

Startup Village (Amsterdam, 2022), AIRLab (Delft, 2019), NucTech meeting Invited speaker

(Delft, 2018), Delft-Leiden Deep Learning Seminars (Leiden, 2019)

Deep Learning MSc course TUDelft (2019) Invited lecturer

Outstanding Reviewer: CVPR (2021, 2022), ICCV (2021), ECCV (2022), AWARD

BMVC(2021, 2022)

Best paper award for the Workshop on Hands, ECCVw (2018)

ICCV (2023,2021), CVPR (2021), ECCV (2020, 2016, 2014), ICIP (2018, 2016) International conferences LOCAL CONFERENCES/EVENTS

Video Understanding Symposium (2023), NCCV (2018 - 2023), NVPHBV

(2017), ICT.Open (2016, 2012)

CVPR, ECCV/ICCV, BMVC, WACV, ICPR, TIP, IJCV Reviewer (since 2012) Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, C/C++, Caffe, Torch, PHP, Programming

Java, OpenCV, Dlib, Shogun, LibSVM, VlFeat, Yael, Matlab